A Guide to the James J. Kilpatrick Papers 1963-1977
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
The James J. Kilpatrick Papers 1963-1977
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
6626-g
15,000 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The Library acquired these papers from James J. Kilpatrick on 3 May 1977.
Scope and Content Information
The collection contains reader mail, 1975-1977; speeches and related research and correspondence; manuscripts for his syndicated column, 1976 January to June; a 1974 interview with President Nixon regarding the Watergate scandal; articles, chiefly for National Review and related correspondence; research files particularly on Nixon, Watergate and the 1968 Democratic Convention; an appointment calendar and an account book.
Contents List
- Reader Mail Jan-Jun 1975
  - Abortion Apr-Jun 1975 (Box 1)
  - Abzug, Bella Apr 1975 (Box 1)
  - "Agronsky & Co." Apr 1975 (Box 1)
  - Amnesty Jun 1975 (Box 1)
  - Baseball Mar-Jun 1975 (Box 1)
  - Bicentennial Feb-Jul 1975 (Box 1)
  - Bureaucracy Jan-Jun 1975 (Box 1)
  - Business May-Jun 1975, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Capitalism Jun 1975 (Box 1)
  - Central Intelligence Agency Dec 1974-Jun 1975 (Box 1)
  - Child Development Apr 1975 (Box 1)
  - Cigarettes Mar-May 1975 (Box 1)
  - Communism Jan-Jun 1975 (Box 1)
  - Congress Apr-Jul 1975 (Box 1)
  - Conservatism Jan-Jun 1975 (Box 1)
  - Constitution Jan-Jun 1975 (Box 1)
  - Consumerism Jan-Jun 1975 (Box 1)
  - Courts Mar 1975 (Box 1)
  - Crime Feb-Jun 1975, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Crime [1975] (Box 2)
  - Economy Jan-Jun 1975, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Education Jan-Jul 1975, 4 folders (Box 2)
  - Energy Jan-Jul 1975 (Box 2)
  - Environment Jan-Apr 1975 (Box 2)
  - Equal Rights Amendment Dec 1974-May 1975 (Box 3)
  - Fan Mail Feb-Jun 1975 (Box 3)
  - Federal Communications Commission Feb 1975 (Box 3)
  - Federal Government Feb-Mar 1975 (Box 3)
  - Food Jan-Mar 1975 (Box 3)
  - Ford, Gerald Apr-Jun 1975 (Box 3)
  - Foreign Affairs Jan-Jun 1975, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Gun Control Feb-Jun 1975 (Box 3)
  - Greece May 1975 (Box 3)
  - Health Care Jan-Jul 1975
  - History Mar 1975 (Box 3)
  - Hoover, Herbert Jun 1975 (Box 3)
  - Kennedy, Edward Jan-Jun 1975 (Box 3)
  - Kennedy, John May-Jun 1975 (Box 3)
  - Labor Apr-Jun 1975 (Box 3)
  - Law Jan-Jun 1975 (Box 3)
  - Legal Services Jun 1975 (Box 3)
  - Marijuana Dec 1974-Jun 1975 (Box 3)
  - Minimum Wage Apr 1975 (Box 3)
  - National Science Foundation Mar-May 1975 (Box 3)
  - Newspaper Writing Mar-Apr 1975 (Box 4)
  - Nixon, Richard Jan-Jun 1975 (Box 4)
  - Nut Mail Mar 1975 (Box 4)
  - Panama Canal Jan-Jun 1975 (Box 4)
  - Patriotism Apr-Jun 1975 (Box 4)
  - Pegler, Westbrook Apr-Jan 1975 (Box 4)
  - Pensions May 1975 (Box 4)
  - Plants Feb 1975 (Box 4)
  - Poetry Jan 1975 (Box 4)
  - Politics Jan-Jul 1975 (Box 4)
  - Pornography Jan-Jun 1975 (Box 4)
  - Prayer Apr-May 1975 (Box 4)
  - Press Jan-Jun 1975 (Box 4)
  - Privacy Feb 1975 (Box 4)
  - Public Works Jun 1975 (Box 4)
  - Race Feb-Jun 1975 (Box 4)
  - Religion Dec 1974-Jun 1975 (Box 4)
  - Reprint Permission Apr-Jun 1975 (Box 4)
  - Satire Jan-May 1975 (Box 4)
  - Spain May 1975 (Box 4)
  - Speeches Regretted Jan-Feb 1975 (Box 4)
  - Speeches Regretted Mar-Jun 1975 (Box 5)
  - Supreme Court Jan-Jun 1975 (Box 5)
  - Texas Jun 1975 (Box 5)
  - Transportation Jan-May 1975 (Box 5)
  - Trucks Feb-Apr 1975 (Box 5)
  - Truman, Harry May 1975 (Box 5)
  - United Nations Jan-Mar 1975 (Box 5)
  - Vietnam Feb-May 1975, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Wallace, George May-Jun 1975 (Box 5)
  - Welfare Jan-Jun 1975 (Box 5)
  - Writing Feb-Jul 1975 (Box 5)
- Reader Mail Jul-Dec 1975
  - Abortion Oct 1975 (Box 5)
  - "Agronsky and Company" Nov-Dec 1975 (Box 5)
  - Alaska Sep 1975 (Box 5)
  - Animals Sep 1975 (Box 5)
  - Armed Services Jul 1975 (Box 5)
  - Baseball Jul 1975 (Box 5)
  - Beadle Bumble Fund Dec 1975 (Box 5)
  - Bicentennial Jul-Nov 1975 (Box 5)
  - Bilderbergers Nov 1975 (Box 5)
  - Books Aug 1975 (Box 5)
  - Bureaucracy Nov-Dec 1975 (Box 5)
  - Business Jul-Aug 1975 (Box 5)
  - Business Sep-Dec 1975 (Box 6)
  - Byrd Memorial Jun-Oct 1975 (Box 6)
  - Campaign 1976 Sep 1975 (Box 6)
  - Campaign of 1976: Ford, Gerald Aug-Oct 1975 (Box 6)
  - Campaign of 1976: Reagan, Ronald Aug-Dec 1975 (Box 6)
  - Central Intelligence Agency Jul-Dec 1975 (Box 6)
  - Cities Jul-Oct 1975 (Box 6)
  - Civil Rights Mar 1975 (Box 6)
  - Communism Aug-Dec 1975 (Box 6)
  - Confederacy Jul 1975 (Box 6)
  - Congress Aug-Dec 1975 (Box 6)
  - Conservation Jul-Dec 1975, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Constitution Jul-Dec 1975 (Box 6)
  - Consumerism Jul-Dec 1975 (Box 6)
  - Cranberg Rule Jul 1975 (Box 6)
  - Crime Jul-Nov 1975 (Box 6)
  - Dirigibles Jul-Oct 1975 (Box 6)
  - Economy Sep-Dec 1975 (Box 6)
  - Education May-Dec 1975, 5 folders (Box 7)
  - Elections Aug-Oct 1975 (Box 7)
  - Energy Jul-Nov 1975 (Box 7)
  - Environment Jul-Dec 1975 (Box 7)
  - Equal Rights Amendment Jul-Aug 1975 (Box 7)
  - Fan Mail Jul-Dec 1975 (Box 7)
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation Nov 1975 (Box 7)
  - Flood Insurance Nov 1975 (Box 7)
  - Ford, Betty Sep 1975 (Box 7)
  - Foreign Affairs Jul-Dec 1975 (Box 8)
  - Government Aug-Dec 1975 (Box 8)
  - Grants Sep 1975 (Box 8)
  - Gun Control Jul-Dec 1975 (Box 8)
  - Harrington Affair Jun-Aug 1975 (Box 8)
  - Health Care May-Dec 1975, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Highways Aug 1975 (Box 8)
  - Invitations Nov 1975 (Box 8)
  - Ireland Trip Sep-Nov 1975 (Box 8)
  - Journalism Aug-Oct 1975 (Box 8)
  - Kennedy, John F. Oct-Dec 1975 (Box 8)
  - Labor May-Dec 1975 (Box 8)
  - Law Jul-Dec 1975 (Box 8)
  - Legal Services Nov-Dec 1975 (Box 8)
  - Libertarian Party Sep-Nov 1975 (Box 8)
  - Litter Sep-Dec 1975 (Box 8)
  - Nation's Business Aug-Nov 1975 (Box 8)
  - National Review Aug-Oct 1975 (Box 8)
  - New York City Dec 1975 (Box 8)
  - Newspapers Jul-Nov 1975 (Box 8)
  - Nixon, Richard Jul-Dec 1975 (Box 9)
  - Nut Mail Dec 1975 (Box 9)
  - Panama Canal Aug-Oct 1975 (Box 9)
  - Patriotism Sep 1975 (Box 9)
  - Pitts-Lee Jul-Oct 1975 (Box 9)
  - Poetry Aug 1975 (Box 9)
  - Politics Jun-Dec 1975 (Box 9)
  - Population Jun-Jul 1975 (Box 9)
  - Pornography Dec 1975 (Box 9)
  - Post Office Sep 1975 (Box 9)
  - Press Jul-Dec 1975 (Box 9)
  - Privacy Oct-Nov 1975 (Box 9)
  - Race Jul-Dec 1975 (Box 9)
  - Regulation Jul-Oct 1979 (Box 9)
  - Religion Jul-Nov 1979 (Box 9)
  - Reprint Permission Jul-Dec 1975 (Box 9)
  - Rule Six Sep-Oct 1975 (Box 9)
  - Satire Apr 1974-Oct 1975 (Box 9)
  - Scotus Dec 1975 (Box 9)
  - "Sixty Minutes" Apr-Sep 1975, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Social Security Jul-Dec 1975 (Box 9)
  - South Nov-Dec 1975 (Box 9)
  - Space Aug 1975 (Box 9)
  - Speech Regrets Jul-Dec 1975 (Box 9)
  - Supreme Court Oct-Dec 1975 (Box 10)
  - Tankers Sep-Oct 1975 (Box 10)
  - Taxes Aug-Sep 1975 (Box 10)
  - United Nations Sep 1975 (Box 10)
  - Washington Star Syndicate Jul-Nov 1975 (Box 10)
  - Welfare Jul-Dec 1975 (Box 10)
  - Writing Jul-Dec 1975 (Box 10)
  - WTOP Dec 1975 (Box 10)
- Reader Mail Jan-Jun 1976
  - Abortion Feb-Jun 1976 (Box 10)
  - "Agronsky and Company" Jan-Jun 1976 (Box 10)
  - Aliens Mar 1976 (Box 10)
  - Animals May 1976 (Box 10)
  - B-1 Bomber May-Jun 1976 (Box 10)
  - Bail Apr 1976 (Box 10)
  - Bicentennial Jan-Jun 1976 (Box 10)
  - Books Jan-Jun 1976 (Box 10)
  - Brown, Jerry May-Jun 1976 (Box 10)
  - Bureaucracy Jan-Jun 1976 (Box 10)
  - Business Jan-Jun 1976 (Box 10)
  - Callaway, Howard (Bo) Mar-Apr 1976 (Box 11)
  - Campaign of 1976: Carter, Jimmy Mar-Jun 1976 (Box 11)
  - Campaign of 1976: Conventions Feb-Apr 1976 (Box 11)
  - Censorship Jan 1975 (Box 11)
  - Central Intelligence Agency Jan-Jun 1976 (Box 11)
  - Child Development Jan-May 1976 (Box 11)
  - Common Cause Feb-Mar 1976 (Box 11)
  - Communism Jan-May 1976 (Box 11)
  - Congress Feb-Apr 1976 (Box 11)
  - Conservation Feb-Apr 1976 (Box 11)
  - Constitution Jan-Jun 1976 (Box 11)
  - Courts Feb 1976 (Box 11)
  - Crime Jan-May 1976 (Box 11)
  - Dirigibles 1976 (Box 11)
  - Economy Jan-May 1976 (Box 11)
  - Education Jan-Sep 1976 (Box 11)
  - Elections Dec 1975 (Box 11)
  - Energy Jan-Jun 1976 (Box 11)
  - Environment Mar 1976 (Box 11)
  - Equal Rights Amendment Jan-Jun 1976 (Box 11)
  - Fan Mail Jan-Jun 1976 (Box 11)
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation May-Jun 1976 (Box 11)
  - Flood Insurance Jan 1976 (Box 11)
  - Fluoridation Jan-May 1976 (Box 11)
  - Foreign Affairs Sep 1975-Apr 1976 (Box 11)
  - Foreign Affairs May-Jun 1976 (Box 12)
  - Fund for Investigative Journalism Feb 1976 (Box 12)
  - Funerals May-Jun 1976 (Box 12)
  - Government Jan-May 1976 (Box 12)
  - Gun Control Jan-Apr 1976 (Box 12)
  - Happiness Column Feb-Mar 1976 (Box 12)
  - Hays, Wayne May-Jun 1976 (Box 12)
  - Health Care: Dentistry Jan 1976 (Box 12)
  - Health Care: General Jan-Jun 1976, 3 folders (Box 12)
  - Health Care: Laetrile Aug 1974-Apr 1976, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Health, Education, and Welfare, Dept. of Feb 1976 (Box 12)
  - Hearst, Patty Mar 1976 (Box 12)
  - Humphrey, Hubert Jan-May 1976 (Box 12)
  - Hunt, Howard Apr 1976 (Box 12)
  - Judges Jan 1976 (Box 13)
  - Kennedy, Edward Apr 1976 (Box 13)
  - Kennedy, John F.: Assassination Jan 1976 (Box 13)
  - Labor Jan-Jun 1976 (Box 13)
  - Language Apr 1976 (Box 13)
  - Law Jan-May 1976 (Box 13)
  - Libertarians Feb 1976 (Box 13)
  - McCarthy, Eugene Feb 1976 (Box 13)
  - McGovern, George Jan 1976 (Box 13)
  - Nation's Business Feb-Jun 1976 (Box 13)
  - National Science Foundation Jan 1976 (Box 13)
  - Newspaper Writing Jan-May 1976 (Box 13)
  - Nixon, Richard Jan-Apr 1976 (Box 13)
  - No Fault Insurance Apr-May 1976 (Box 13)
  - Nut Mail Jan-Apr 1976 (Box 13)
  - Occupational Safety and Health Administration May 1976 (Box 13)
  - Panama Canal Apr-Jun 1976 (Box 13)
  - Poetry Mar 1976 (Box 13)
  - Politics Dec 1975-Jun 1976 (Box 13)
  - Population Feb 1976 (Box 13)
  - Postal Service Jan-Apr 1976 (Box 13)
  - Press Jan-Jun 1976 (Box 13)
  - Princeton Apr 1976 (Box 13)
  - Race Jan-Jun 1979 (Box 13)
  - Reagan, Ronald Jan-Jun 1976 (Box 14)
  - Religion Jan-Jun 1976 (Box 14)
  - Reprint Permission Jan-Jun 1976 (Box 14)
  - Science Feb 1976 (Box 14)
  - Sex Mar-May 1976 (Box 14)
  - "Sixty Minutes" Dec 1975-Mar 1976 (Box 14)
  - Speech Regrets Jan-Jun 1976 (Box 14)
  - Supreme Court Jan-Apr 1976 (Box 14)
  - Taxation Dec 1975-May 1976 (Box 14)
  - Television Jan-Apr 1976 (Box 14)
  - Thank Yous Jan-Apr 1976 (Box 14)
  - Transportation Jan-Apr 1976 (Box 14)
  - Treasure Mar 1976 (Box 14)
  - Triangle Publications Feb 1976 (Box 14)
  - United Nations Feb-Mar 1976 (Box 14)
  - Veterans Mar-Jun 1976 (Box 14)
  - Voting Rights Apr-May 1976 (Box 14)
  - War Powers Feb 1976 (Box 14)
  - Washington Star Syndicate Jan-Apr 1976 (Box 14)
  - Watergate Apr 1976 (Box 14)
  - Welfare Jan-Mar 1976 (Box 14)
  - Writing Jan-May 1976 (Box 14)
  - WTOP Jan-Mar 1976 (Box 14)
- Reader Mail Jul-Dec 1976
  - Abortion Aug-Dec 1976, 2 folders (Box 15)
  - "Agronsky and Company" Oct 1976 (Box 15)
  - Air Bags Aug 1976 (Box 15)
  - Air Lines Aug 1976 (Box 15)
  - American Cause Aug 1976 (Box 15)
  - Amnesty 1976 (Box 15)
  - Armed Forces Nov-Dec 1976 (Box 15)
  - Assassinations Oct-Dec 1976 (Box 15)
  - Bicentennial Jun-Sep 1976 (Box 15)
  - Books Jun-Dec 1976 (Box 15)
  - Brown, Edmund "Jerry" Jun 1976 (Box 15)
  - Bureaucracy Jun-Dec 1976, 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Business Feb-Oct 1976 (Box 15)
  - Callaway, Howard H. (Bo) Oct 1976 (Box 15)
  - Campaign of 1976: Carter, Jimmy Jun-Dec 1976, 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Campaign of 1976: Ford, Gerald Jul-Nov 1976 (Box 15)
  - Campaign of 1976: Reagan, Ronald Jul-Sep 1976 (Box 15)
  - Censorship Nov 1976 (Box 15)
  - Child Development Jul-Aug 1976 (Box 15)
  - Christmas Dec 1976 (Box 15)
  - Communism Jul-Oct 1976 (Box 16)
  - Congress Jun 1976-Jan 1977 (Box 16)
  - Conservation Dec 1976 (Box 16)
  - Conservatism Jul-Dec 1976 (Box 16)
  - Constitution Jul-Dec 1976 (Box 16)
  - Consumerism Jun 1976 (Box 16)
  - Cooking Dec 1976 (Box 16)
  - Courts Nov 1976 (Box 16)
  - Crime Aug-Dec 1976 (Box 16)
  - Defense Jul 1976 (Box 16)
  - Do Nothing 1976 (Box 16)
  - Dole, Robert Aug 1976 (Box 16)
  - Economy Aug 1976-Jan 1977 (Box 16)
  - Education Jul-Nov 1976 (Box 16)
  - Elections Oct 1976 (Box 16)
  - Energy Jan-Oct 1976 (Box 16)
  - Environment Aug-Nov 1976 (Box 16)
  - Family Dec 1976-Jan 1977 (Box 16)
  - Fan Mail Jun-Dec 1976 (Box 16)
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation Jul-Aug 1976 (Box 16)
  - Federal Communications Commission Jun-Jul 1976 (Box 16)
  - Federal Reserve System Jul 1976 (Box 16)
  - Fluoridation Dec 1976 (Box 16)
  - Foreign Affairs Apr-Dec 1976 (Box 16)
  - Funerals Aug-Sep 1976 (Box 16)
  - Gun Control Apr-Dec 1976 (Box 16)
  - Health Care May-Dec 1976, 2 folders (Box 16)
  - History Jun 1976 (Box 17)
  - Human Events Jul 1976 (Box 17)
  - Immigration Jul 1976 (Box 17)
  - International Platform Association Aug 1976 (Box 17)
  - Invitations Aug-Oct 1976 (Box 17)
  - Kennedy, Edward Apr-Sep 1976 (Box 17)
  - Kennedy, John F, Oct 1976 (Box 17)
  - Labor Jul-Nov 1976 (Box 17)
  - Laetrile Apr-Dec 1976 (Box 17)
  - Land Use Oct 1976 (Box 17)
  - Law Jun-Dec 1976 (Box 17)
  - Libertarians Feb 1975-Oct 1976 (Box 17)
  - McCarthy, Eugene Nov 1976 (Box 17)
  - Military Jun-Aug 1976 (Box 17)
  - Minority Parties Aug 1976 (Box 17)
  - Mondale, Walter Jul 1976 (Box 17)
  - Nation's Business Jul-Dec 1976 (Box 17)
  - New Republic Flap Dec 1976 (Box 17)
  - Newspaper Writing Jul-Oct 1976 (Box 17)
  - Nixon, Richard Aug-Dec 1976 (Box 17)
  - Occupational Safety and Health Administration Jun-Dec 1976 (Box 17)
  - Panama Canal Aug-Dec 1976 (Box 17)
  - Permissions Jul-Sep 1976 (Box 17)
  - Poetry Aug-Oct 1976 (Box 17)
  - Politics May-Dec 1976, 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Pollution Aug-Dec 1976 (Box 18)
  - Postal Service Jul-Aug 1976 (Box 18)
  - Press Mar 1976-Jan 1977 (Box 18)
  - Privacy Dec 1976 (Box 18)
  - Race Jun-Dec 1976, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Reading Jul 1976 (Box 18)
  - Religion Aug 1976-Feb 1977 (Box 18)
  - Reprint Permission Jun-Dec 1976 (Box 18)
  - Right to Work Jun 1976 (Box 18)
  - Satire Sep 1976-Jan 1977 (Box 18)
  - Sex Jun 1976 (Box 18)
  - "Sixty Minutes" Jul-Sep 1976 (Box 18)
  - Social Security Jan 1976 (Box 18)
  - Socialism Feb 1977 (Box 18)
  - Speech Regrets Jun-Dec 1976 (Box 18)
  - Supreme Court Jun-Jul 1976 (Box 18)
  - Taxation Jun-Dec 1976 (Box 18)
  - Thank Yous Aug 1976-Jan 1977 (Box 18)
  - Treasure Aug 1976 (Box 18)
  - Tuna Dec 1976 (Box 18)
  - United Nations Jul 1976 (Box 18)
  - Urban Affairs Jul-Sep 1976 (Box 18)
  - Wars Oct 1976 (Box 18)
  - Washington Star Syndicate Jul-Dec 1976 (Box 18)
  - Welfare Oct 1976 (Box 18)
  - Writing Jul-Dec 1976 (Box 18)
- Speech Files (Speech manuscripts are primarily in the first three folders; others folders usually contain only research notes and correspondence)
  - Speech: Naturalized Citizens 11 Jul 1967 (Box 19)
  - Speeches and Related Material Nov 1968-Apr 1970, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Virginia Press Association, Richmond, Virginia 5 Jan 1974 (Box 19)
  - Ohio University, Chillicothe, Ohio 15 Jan 1974 (Box 19)
  - University of Wisconsin, Oshkosh, Wisconsin 16 Jan 1974 (Box 19)
  - United Fruit and Vegetable Association 6 Feb 1974 (Box 19)
  - Cumberland Law School 6 Feb 1974 (Box 19)
  - IBM Managers' Dinner 10 Feb 1974 (Box 19)
  - Women's Club, Richmond, Virginia 11 Feb 1974 (Box 19)
  - University of Nevada, Reno 19 Feb 1974 (Box 19)
  - Wright University 4 Mar 1974 (Box 19)
  - William and Mary, Williamsburg, Virginia 11 Mar 1974 (Box 19)
  - Clemson University, Clemson, South Carolina 12 Mar 1974 (Box 19)
  - St. John's Dinner Club, Jacksonville, Florida 18 Mar 1974 (Box 19)
  - University of Iowa, Ames 9 Apr 1974 (Box 19)
  - Missouri Valley College, Marshall, Missouri 10 Apr 1974 (Box 19)
  - University of Richmond, Richmond, Virginia 17 Apr 1974 (Box 19)
  - University of Tennessee 22-24 Apr 1974 (Box 19)
  - Chamber of Commerce of the United States, Washington, D.C. 30 Apr 1974 (Box 19)
  - Princeton University, Princeton, New Jersey May 1974 (Box 19)
  - Stanford University 8 May 1974 (Box 19)
  - Montana State University, Bozeman, Montana 9 May 1974 (Box 19)
  - Springfield Adult Education Council 15 May 1974 (Box 19)
  - Reading Reform Foundation 16 May 1974 (Box 19)
  - Medallion Award 1 Jun 1974 (Box 19)
  - Pulliam Fellowship, Indianapolis 23 Jul 1974 (Box 19)
  - Caterpillar Tractor 24 Jul 1974 (Box 19)
  - International Platform Association 1 Aug 1974 (Box 19)
  - Legislative Conference, Albuquerque 16 Aug 1974 (Box 19)
  - American Legion 21-22 Aug 1974 (Box 19)
  - American Iron & Steel Institute 13 Sep 1974 (Box 19)
  - Cast Metals 23 Sep 1974 (Box 19)
  - Great Lakes--Southern Milk, Inc. 30 Sep 1974 (Box 19)
  - Villanova University 2 Oct 1974 (Box 20)
  - IBM 4 Oct 1974 (Box 20)
  - George Washington University 10 Oct 1974 (Box 20)
  - Insurance Agents 15 Oct 1974 (Box 20)
  - Denver Executives' Club 8 Nov 1974 (Box 20)
  - Bellevue, Washington 11 Nov 1974 (Box 20)
  - Creighton University 8 Dec 1974 (Box 20)
  - The Business Council 11 Dec 1974 (Box 20)
  - Alabama Ethics Commission 20 Dec 1974 (Box 20)
  - City Charter Committee of Cincinnati 10 Jan 1975 (Box 20)
  - National Council of Farmer Cooperatives 15 Jan 1975 (Box 20)
  - Austin College 23 Jan 1975 (Box 20)
  - Soap and Detergent Manufacturers 30 Jan 1975 (Box 20)
  - Emory University 3 Feb 1975 (Box 20)
  - Northwestern State University of Louisiana 4 Feb 1975 (Box 20)
  - Advertising Club of Washington, D.C. 11 Feb 1975 (Box 20)
  - Nation's Business Taping 13 Feb 1975 (Box 20)
  - University of Southern California 19 Feb 1975 (Box 20)
  - Colorado Press Association 20 Feb 1975 (Box 20)
  - Presidential Classroom 26 Feb 1975 (Box 20)
  - New Britain Woman's Club 6 Mar 1975 (Box 20)
  - Columbia University 13 Mar 1975 (Box 20)
  - Towson State College 14 Mar 1975 (Box 20)
  - Kean College 18 Mar 1975 (Box 20)
  - Glass Containers Manufacturers Institute 27 Mar 1975 (Box 20)
  - Zurich-American Insurance Companies 14 Apr 1975 (Box 20)
  - Hamilton College 15 Apr 1975 (Box 20)
  - Chamber of Commerce of the United States 28 Apr 1975 (Box 20)
  - Life Insurers Conference 29 Apr 1975 (Box 20)
  - Pharmaceutical Manufacturers Association 30 Apr 1975 (Box 20)
  - Mayo Clinic 3 May 1975 (Box 20)
  - White House Correspondents' Association 3 May 1975 (Box 20)
  - Troy-Miami County Library 10 May 1975 (Box 20)
  - Auburn University 15 May 1975 (Box 20)
  - Washington & Lee University 20 May 1975 (Box 20)
  - Association of Presidential Interchange Executives 30 May 1975 (Box 20)
  - American Eagle Award 4 Jun 1975 (Box 20)
  - Dr. Schaffner Meeting 5 Jun 1975 (Box 20)
  - Xavier University 9 Jun 1975 (Box 21)
  - Armco Steel Corporation 9 Jun 1975 (Box 21)
  - National Town Meeting 2 Jul 1975 (Box 21)
  - Parents Without Partners 11 Jul 1975 (Box 21)
  - Jefferson Film Debate 14-18 Jul 1975 (Box 21)
  - Conservative Union Club 17 Jul 1975 (Box 21)
  - Karl Hess debate 18 Jul 1975 (Box 21)
  - Saginaw Radio Spot 31 Jul 1975 (Box 21)
  - International Platform Association 4-8 Aug 1975 (Box 21)
  - Interview with Mrs. Savoldi 21 Aug 1975 (Box 21)
  - Mr. Healey 4 Sep 1975 (Box 21)
  - American Enterprise Institute 11 Sep 1975 (Box 21)
  - President's Commission on Personnel Interchange 19 Sep 1975 (Box 21)
  - Porcelain Enamel Institute 23 Sep 1975 (Box 21)
  - West Virginia Manufacturer's Association 3 Oct 1975 (Box 21)
  - Virginia Association of Professions 4 Oct 1975 (Box 21)
  - Miami University 10 Oct 1975 (Box 21)
  - Brick Institute 4 Nov 1975 (Box 21)
  - Armed Forces Staff College 7 Nov 1975 (Box 21)
  - Byrd Dinner 11 Nov 1975 (Box 21)
  - American Iron & Steel Institute 14 Nov 1975 (Box 21)
  - National Review Twentieth Anniversary 17 Nov 1975 (Box 21)
  - Woodrow Wilson Center for Scholars 4 Dec 1975 (Box 21)
  - Stone & Webster 4 Dec 1975 (Box 21)
  - Association of Southern Colleges 7 Dec 1975 (Box 21)
  - Gastronomes, etc. 13 Dec 1975 (Box 21)
- Radio, TV, and Column Manuscripts
  - Interview with President Nixon May 1974 (Box 21)
  - Manuscripts of Kilpatrick's Syndicated Newspaper Column Jan-Mar 1976 (Box 21)
  - Manuscripts of Kilpatrick's Syndicated Newspaper Column Apr-Jun 1976 (Box 22)
  - WTOP Commentaries 1975 (Box 22)
  - CBS "60 Minutes": Transcripts of "Point/Counterpoint" 1974-1976 (Box 22)
- Magazine Articles and Related Material
  - Conservative View: Correspondence Dec 1966 (Box 22)
  - Encyclopedia Britannica: "A Few Reflections on the Unbridgeable Gap" Aug 1968 (Box 22)
  - Harper's: Correspondence May 1967-Oct 1968 (Box 22)
  - Nation's Business: "The Age of NO" Sep 1972 (Box 22)
  - National Review: Correspondence Aug 1965-Mar 1974, n.d. (Box 22)
  - National Review: Rhodesia May 1967 (Box 22)
  - National Review: USS Liberty Jun-Jul 1967 (Box 22)
  - National Review: "Term's End" Jul 1967 (Box 22)
  - National Review: "Crisis Seven" Sep-Dec 1967 (Box 22)
  - National Review: "Romney: Salesman on the Move" Oct-Dec 1967 (Box 22)
  - National Review: 100 Days of Nixon Jul 1968-May 1969 (Box 22)
  - National Review: "Notes from the Campaign Trail" Nov 1968 (Box 23)
  - National Review: "Hi, There! Your Next Senator..." Mar-Apr 1971 (Box 23)
  - National Review: "Henry Jackson, Man of the Middle" Feb 1972 (Box 23)
  - National Review: "George McGovern Prairie Preacher" Feb, Aug 1972 (Box 23)
  - National Review: "HHH--He Means to be Number One" Apr 1972 (Box 23)
  - Playboy: Correspondence Sep 1972-Aug 1973 (Box 23)
  - Playboy: "The Bijoona in 615" Dec 1972-Jan 1973 (Box 23)
  - Prism: "Something's Happened to Tom!" Oct-Dec 1975 (Box 23)
  - Private Practice: "New Year...New Headache" Nov 1968-Apr 1969 (Box 23)
  - Saturday Evening Post: Speaking Out Piece Feb 1968 (Box 23)
  - Saturday Review: Correspondence Mar 1969-Sep 1970 (Box 23)
  - Southern Living Magazine: "A Smokiness so Vague in the Air" Jun-Aug 1968 (Box 23)
  - United States Information Agency: "An Appraisal of American Conservatism" Dec 1971-Aug 1972 (Box 23)
- Research Files
  - Richard Nixon (The Future of the GOP) 1963-1978 (Box 23)
  - Project Mohole May-Aug 1966 (Box 23)
  - National Educational Television: "State of the Union--1967" Jan-Feb 1967 (Box 23)
  - Correspodence re Howard W. Smith's Papers May-Jun 1967 (Box 23)
  - Correspondence: Little, Brown and Company Sep-Nov 1967 (Box 23)
  - Democratic National Convention Jul-Aug 1968, 2 folders (Box 23)
  - Mansfield, Mike Mar 1969-Apr 1975 (Box 24)
  - Impeachment of Richard Nixon Jan-Nov 1973, Feb-May 1974, n.d. (Box 24)
  - Watergate 1973 (Box 24)
  - Appointment Calendar 1974-1975 (Box 24)
  - National Right to Work Committee Jun 1976 (Box 24)
  - Greece and Brazil n.d. (Box 24)
  - New Hampshire n.d. (Box 24)
  - Account Book 1967-1969 (Box 24)